Fueled by the fire and anointing of the Holy Spirit
Prophet T.B. Joshua prays for the people one by one, and any contrary spirit within them is exposed.
Who are you?
Spirit of delay.
What have you done to her?
The spirit of prostitution.
How did you enter her?
Through dreams.
The spirit of prostitution is cast out.
I'm free! I'm delivered! Thank You, Jesus!
TESTIMONY CONTINUES
Emmanuel!
(God With Us - Matthew 1:23)
Children of God, Emmanuel!
My name is Ikeaguzi Rita.
The people standing beside me are my mother and my elder brothers.
My testimony goes like this:
When I was staying in a village in 2012, a lady came to me.
She asked me if I wanted to travel out of the country.
I agreed and was very excited because I wanted to travel
and I thought that travelling was like Heaven.
I never knew that the journey I would take was very risky.
Then, the lady said she had called a man who would come to my house to speak to my family.
That was how the man came to our house and spoke to my parents and me.
The man said that I would travel to Europe; then, he asked me if I could hustle.
I asked the man which kind of hustle he meant.
The man said, "Anything to do with fashion like women's hair or jewelry".
Then I agreed that I could do it and got ready to travel.
The following day, the man said that I should meet him in Benin;
so, I went to Benin to meet the man.
When I arrived in Benin, I was with five other girls in a hotel room.
I asked the other girls but none of them knew what they were going to do in Europe;
all the man said was that they would hustle.
Then, we started the journey.
When we travelled, we passed some countries but I do not know the names.
Then, we passed through the desert to get to Libya.
When we passed through the desert, it was not easy; we were between life and death.
When we passed through the desert, we spent four days in a jeep.
The jeep was supposed to carry 10 people but they packed us in like sardines, so, we were 90.
You mean 90 people - nine zero (90)?
Yes, we were 90 people in a jeep.
You're 90 people in a vehicle that is meant for just 10.
Yes
Both males and females, we sat one in front of the other; they squeezed us in like ants.
Then, we passed through the desert; after passing through the desert, we arrived in Libya.
When we arrived in Libya, the man told us that it was the European country we were travelling to.
I did not know then that Libya was an African country.
The man separated us and took me to a lady; they hustled at her place.
I stayed with the lady with some of the girls and some of the girls stayed with the man.
One day, the man said that we should go and hustle.
I told the man that I would not hustle because he didn't tell me that to hustle means
doing prostitution in Europe.
The man said that I should start prostitution in Libya.
I told the man that he didn't tell me or my parents that it was for prostitution.
The man told me that I had to do prostitution.
Otherwise he would make trouble with my family in the village.
He even threatened to kill me saying that no one would ask of me; I would just die like that.
I felt I had no choice than to do the prostitution.
When I was at the lady's place - they call it 'Connection House' -
I would be in a room and men would be sent to me.
From five to eight men would come and sleep with me,
they would give me money and the man would take the money from me.
So, on a daily basis, you were meeting up to eight men,
you were kept in this room, and the men would come and meet you there, sleep with you.
Whatever money you collected from them would be given to this man,
who was acting as if he was your slave master.
Yes
One day, I ran away from the man.
When I ran away from the man....
Sister, before you ran away, for how long had you been there in Libya doing this?
I left Nigeria in 2012 and I came back in 2014; I was in Libya for almost two years.
I ran away from the man and got to another city in Libya, where I met a Cameroonian guy.
From there, we went to Cameroon and from Cameroon, we went to Chad.
Okay, so you started a relationship with this man from Cameroon
and he took you from Libya back to his country of Cameroon,
and then the two of you went to the nation of Chad.
What were you doing in Chad?
The man said we should go to Chad because of his art work, so, he brought me to Chad.
When we arrived in Chad, the man said that he was a painter but he did not get any work in Chad.
I don't even know if he could paint or not because I never saw his work.
The only thing the man used to do was to sleep around with different women,
sometimes, he would beat and curse me.
One day, I told the man that I didn't need this kind of relationship.
I was lucky, one fateful day, I met a Nigerian lady;
when I explained my story, she helped me get a job in Chad.
When I was working, the lady helped me look for another job in a beer parlour.
I started working in a beer parlour; when I was working there, I met a Nigerian man.
The Nigerian man told me that he had a sister in Europe and asked if I wanted to go there.
That is how I was deceived again.
I told him that the travelling I attempted before was very risky.
He told me that this journey was to Europe, not Libya and I agreed.
I spoke to a lady on the phone, who said I would give her 36,000 euros.
But then, I didn't know the value of 36,000 euros; I thought it was like 36,000 naira!
They continued talking to me, deceiving me that before five months,
I would have paid off the money and started to help my family - to relieve their suffering.
I agreed so, they took me to a native doctor.
They said the native doctor would prepare my body so that when I got to Europe,
I would see a man to help me and give me money.
My family never went to native doctors; it was then, I was introduced to native doctors.
The native doctor prepared my body by giving me a fowl.
and said that I should spin the fowl around my head several times and repeat what he said.
The native doctor said I should be naked and he brought a knife and other things.
The native doctors said that if I did not give the lady the money, I would die
and if I handed the lady over to the police, I would die.
He also said that if I sent money from the lady back to Nigeria, I would also die.
I said, "Okay, no problem".
Then, the native doctor took my finger nails, toe nails, pubic hair and underwear.
He kept those things and they are still with him now.
After I finished everything at the herbalist's, I travelled.
When I travelled, the lady's brother handed me over to another person.
I followed the person to travel; I was told that I would not travel by road but by air.
As we were going, we passed Lagos, Nigeria; I thought I would get my passport there.
When I asked the man, he said that it was not his business that I was just handed over to him;
he said he did not know what I was talking about, then we left.
We passed some countries, just like the first journey and we entered the desert again.
When we got to the desert - the first time travelled was better than the second time.
The second journey was very hard; I saw a lot of things on the way.
Some of them would demand for money because they would act like police to you.
But if you don't have any money to pay them, they will beat you and they can even kill you.
Many people died in the desert; many people even died in the jeep.
They surround the jeep with sticks to hold on; if you don't hold on well to the stick, you will fall and die.
Then, we got to Libya.
It is from Tripoli they 'push people' to Italy.
I spent one month and two weeks in Tripoli, before we crossed to Italy in a boat.
We just want you to explain how you were pushed into the ocean to go across to Italy.
Can you just describe the kind of boats that you entered,
and what it looked like and how many of you were inside?
The 'lapa-lapa' is a rubber boat.
We were 90 in the boat but normally that boat is supposed to carry 12 or 13 people.
Okay, so you're saying it is like a rubber boat.
Just a small rubber boat that is supposed to just contain 12 to 13 people,
but more than 90 people were on top of this boat.
Yes, and that was how we entered the sea.
Okay, and none of you in that boat could swim.
None of us could swim.
When we set out on the sea, it was 10pm; we arrived in Italian waters at 8am.
We slept in the boat on the sea before the Italian rescuers rescued us.
When the Italian rescuers rescued us, we were put into a camp.
I called the lady that I had arrived in Italy, she said that she would come and pick me up.
She picked me up and I stayed in her house.
The following day, she said that I should get ready to work.
When I asked her which work, she said, "Prostitution".
Then she told me that the 36,000 euros I was to pay her was equal to 7 million naira.
7 million naira?
Even more than 7 million naira is equal to 36,000 euro.
I told the lady that I could not pay the money, because it was too much.
I told her that she did not tell me it was seven million naira, I thought it was 30,000 naira.
The lady said that I must pay the money and if I reported her to the police,
I should remember the ritual I did in Nigeria - I would die.
So, I felt that I had no choice. The lady was also doing prostitution.
The lady took me to where they did the prostitution, which was on the road.
When a car came along, the lady would settle the price because the lady speaks their language.
After the lady would speak for me, she would tell me to enter the car;
I would enter the car and follow the man.
The lowest price would be from 10 to 20 euros, but if somebody wanted to take you to a hotel,
it would cost 50-100 euros. The lowest price was 10-20 euros.
I would sleep with different men, up to 10, 5 or 6.
One day, I could not bear it anymore; I told the lady that I wanted to go.
At this point, you had been in Italy prostituting for how many months,
when you told the lady you wanted to leave?
I stayed with the lady for eight months before I told her that I wanted to leave.
Then the lady said that I could not leave her and she started calling her people.
I told the lady that if she did not let me go, I would go to the police station and report her.
Even if I were to die, I was not afraid of death.
I wanted to go to the (police)station and tell them that I wanted to go back to my country.
Then, one day, I bought a second-hand phone with a SIM card already inside it.
I saw some numbers already stored in the phone so, I called one of them;
a man picked up the call, he was from Nigeria.
I told the man how I felt that I wanted to leave Italy because I was tired of my way of life.
The man said that if I felt that way and I didn't have anywhere to go, I could stay at his place.
I went to the man's place and stayed there.
This is someone you never knew before. You just saw a random phone number on a phone.
A second-hand phone that you bought in Italy, and you just called that man and agreed to go to him.
Yes, I bought a second-hand phone with a SIM card already inside of it.
I saw many numbers in the phone - I have never met the man before;
we just spoke on the phone, I had never seen him before; I didn't know him.
So that's how you ran away from that woman
who you were doing prostitution with, and you went to this guy.
Yes
Before I went to that man, he told me that he was working.
I did not know that he did not have a job; he was begging on the streets.
When I got to his place, I found out that he did not have a job and he was not doing anything.
I also didn't have anything to do; so, I joined him to beg because I didn't want to do prostitution.
It now led you to start begging on the streets.
Yes, we would go together to beg on the streets.
When we were together begging on the streets,
I told the guy that I was tired and wanted to go back to Nigeria.
He told me that I didn't know what I was saying and asked me how I could say that -
from Europe I wanted to return to Nigeria.
He said that people in Nigeria are suffering and looking for opportunity to travel -
for me to say I wanted to go back to Nigeria was not normal.
I told him that I was normal; I was tired of that way of life.
The guy told me that I should travel to Switzerland.
So, I travelled to Switzerland to seek for asylum.
When I travelled to Switzerland to seek for asylum,
I stayed there for three months in a camp.
They fed me and clothed me because I was staying there under care of the government.
Eventually, Switzerland rejected me because they said they had taken my fingerprints in Italy
so, they said I should go back to Italy.
In Switzerland, I met another man who I shared my experience with.
He told me that he had a sister in Belgium who would help me with documents to work.
Okay, so once again people of God,
we are listening to this life experience, so that everyone can pick one or two lessons.
Our sister never imagined in her wildest dreams that this was what she would encounter
when she was first told she would travel to Europe; she was expecting greener pastures;
she was expecting a beautiful life, a good job, but what she met was completely opposite.
To the point where she was begging on the streets, prostituting her body to make a living.
She said at this point she was unable to be given asylum in the nation of Switzerland
because of complications regarding her entry into Italy
and she was advised to go to the nation of Belgium.
So tell us sister, what happened when you reached Belgium?
When I got to Belgium, I was told that I could use someone else's documents to work.
When I got to Belgium, the lady said that she could not give me documents to work
because she was using the documents to take money.
I had nothing to do so, I went back to prostitution again.
I did not have anyone to feed me or pay house rent for me.
After doing prostitution for four months, I decided not to do it again - I was tired.
I went to the Belgium government to seek for asylum.
When I went to seek for asylum in Belgium, I told them that I wanted to go back to Nigeria.
When I told them that I wanted to go back to Nigeria, they asked me why.
I explained to them and they said that since I wanted to go back to Nigerian, they would help me.
That was how I returned to Nigeria and went home.
Okay, and when did you return to Nigeria?
I returned to Nigeria on the 9th of this month.
When I watched Emmanuel TV, my faith started to grow. Then, I decided to come back to Nigeria.
When I came back to Nigeria, I came to The SCOAN straight away.
We thank God that our sister is alive to actually tell this story, because we know
many embarked on a similar journey, and they are no longer alive to tell the story
Sister, what happened to you last week at The SCOAN when Prophet T.B. Joshua prayed for you?
When the man of God was praying for people, I had not yet got close to him.
My whole body started shaking.
I didn't know what I was doing.
That is all I can remember.
And that was how you were delivered from that evil spirit that pushed you into prostitution?
Yes.
And to the glory of God, ever since that deliverance last week,
what are the changes you've seen in your life?
There have been a lot of changes -
I don't have the urge to sleep with men anymore and I want to give my life to Christ.
I know God has delivered me and I am delivered forever, in Jesus' name.
Amen. Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
And sister, we just want to understand it. How old are you right now?
I am 25 years old.
Okay, so this journey started when our sister was just 20 years old.
She was aproached in the village by a man who promised to take her abroad to Europe for a better life
but opposite was the case.
We thank God that through it all, here she is today in the presence of God.
And sister, before we listen to your family members, what is your word of advice?
Especially to young people out there, a lot of young people have this impression
that they should travel abroad at all costs, that there'll be greener pastures, a better life there.
And they're not ready to go through the right process or procedure to travel.
As someone that has been on this hellish five-year journey,
what is your advice to them based on your own life experience?
I thank God for my life and I thank the man of God for delivering me from the spirit of prostitution.
My advice to viewers around the world, the youth and especially girls -
they may hear many things about Europe that it is like Heaven there;
I want to advise you that whatever you are doing - whether it is hair styling,
fashion design or sales work - just continue what you are doing.
One day, God will see you through.
I am not saying that people should not travel but if you do, travel in a mature way.
You should not listen to people who say, "I have a salon, supermarket, etc."
They are deceiving you.
If you are to travel, make sure you travel in a mature way; that is my advice to them.
Amen. Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
The confession you are giving right now, is your family hearing this for the first time?
The first time I travelled, my parents were aware of it.
Although, I did not know what I was going to do then.
The second time I travelled, my mother did not know about it;
at a point, I explained to my older brother what I was doing there.
My brother said that if that was what happened and the lady said I should pay her
seven million naira and I should get it through prostitution, it's better that I came home.
My name is Ngozi Ikeaguzi.
The thing your daughter just talked about now, what do you want to say about it?
Mothers and fathers, if you have girls and people approach you
to let your child travel abroad, do not agree because they are deceivers.
Ok, our mother is advising that if anyone approaches you as a parent,
offering to take your child abroad and you know it's not in the right way,
you should not be deceived by them because they're playing a tricky game.
So, mama, you mean that you never knew that your daughter was going to do prostitution abroad?
No, I did not know.
So, now that God has delivered your daughter, what do you want to say?
I thank God.
My name is Stanley Ikeaguzi. I am from Delta State, Nigeria.
I am very happy. I thank God that she came back alive and she promised to give her life to Christ.
Amen! Let't put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
STANDARD FOR LIFE
My name is Ikeaguzi Rita. I'm from Delta State, Nigeria.
The people that stand beside me: These are my mother and my brother.
I was delivered from the spirit of prostitution
After my deliverance, I was set free. I no longer have the urge to sleep with men.
I am free forever!
I am going back to my state to start life anew, I will not go back to prostitution.
As much as you are delivered through our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ,
the man of God, Prophet T.B. Joshua, in line with Emmanuel TV partners all over the world said
that he would not allow you to go empty-handed.
He needs to give you something to start your life anew.
For that reason, Emmanuel TV partners alongside with the man of God, Prophet T.B. Joshua, said
that we should present to you the sum of 150,000 naira.
Thank You, Jesus. Thank you, Man of God. Thank you, Emmanuel TV partners. Thank you. Thank You, Jesus!
Ikeaguzi Rita & Family Receive Cash Gift Of 150,000 Naira
I'm free and I will never go back to my past life of prostitution. I will never go back again, in Jesus name.
Thank you, Man of God. Thank you.
This 150,000 naira that the man of God has blessed me with,
is enough for me to start whatever I am going to do.
I will never go back to my former life, in Jesus' name.
Amen!
Apart from the 150,000 naira, we also present to you the sum of 40,000 for your transportation.
Ikeaguzi Rita & Family Receive A Cash Gift Of 190,000 Naira